<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Developer Tools on Hugo</title><link>https://mc.is-local.org/docs/categories/developer-tools/</link><description>Recent content in Developer Tools on Hugo</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://mc.is-local.org/docs/categories/developer-tools/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Editor plugins</title><link>https://mc.is-local.org/docs/tools/editors/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mc.is-local.org/docs/tools/editors/</guid><description>Visual Studio Code Front Matter Once you go for a static site, you need to think about how you are going to manage your articles. Front matter is a tool that helps you maintain the metadata/front matter of your articles like: creation date, modified date, slug, tile, SEO check, and more. Hugo Helper Hugo Helper is a plugin for Visual Studio Code that has some useful commands for Hugo. The source code can be found here.</description></item><item><title>Front-end interfaces</title><link>https://mc.is-local.org/docs/tools/front-ends/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mc.is-local.org/docs/tools/front-ends/</guid><description>Commercial CloudCannon The intuitive Git-based CMS for your Hugo website. CloudCannon syncs changes from your Git repository and pushes content changes back, so your development and content teams are always in sync. Edit all of your content on the page with visual editing, build entire pages with reusable custom components and then publish confidently. DatoCMS DatoCMS is a fully customizable administrative area for your static websites. Use your favorite website generator, let your clients publish new content independently, and the host the site anywhere you like.</description></item><item><title>Search tools</title><link>https://mc.is-local.org/docs/tools/search/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mc.is-local.org/docs/tools/search/</guid><description>A static website with a dynamic search function? Yes, Hugo provides an alternative to embeddable scripts from Google or other search engines for static websites. Hugo allows you to provide your visitors with a custom search function by indexing your content files directly.
Open-source Pagefind A fully static search library that aims to perform well on large sites, while using as little of your users&amp;rsquo; bandwidth as possible. GitHub Gist for Hugo Workflow This gist contains a simple workflow to create a search index for your static website.</description></item><item><title>Migrate to Hugo</title><link>https://mc.is-local.org/docs/tools/migrations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mc.is-local.org/docs/tools/migrations/</guid><description>This section highlights some projects around Hugo that are independently developed. These tools try to extend the functionality of our static site generator or help you to get started.
Take a look at this list of migration tools if you currently use other blogging tools like Jekyll or WordPress but intend to switch to Hugo instead. They&amp;rsquo;ll take care to export your content into Hugo-friendly formats.
Jekyll Alternatively, you can use the Jekyll import command.</description></item><item><title>Other community projects</title><link>https://mc.is-local.org/docs/tools/other/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mc.is-local.org/docs/tools/other/</guid><description>And for all the other community projects around Hugo:
diego - A CLI tool that integrates with Hugo to assist in importing and utilizing exported social media data from popular services on Hugo websites. Emacs Easy Hugo - Emacs package for writing blog posts in Markdown or org-mode and building your site with Hugo. Hugo SFTP Upload - Sync the local build of your Hugo website with your remote web server via SFTP.</description></item></channel></rss>