<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>About on Hugo</title><link>https://gohugo.io/categories/about/</link><description>Recent content in About on Hugo</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://gohugo.io/categories/about/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Introduction</title><link>https://gohugo.io/about/introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gohugo.io/about/introduction/</guid><description>Hugo is a static site generator written in Go, optimized for speed and designed for flexibility. With its advanced templating system and fast asset pipelines, Hugo renders a complete site in seconds, often less.
Due to its flexible framework, multilingual support, and powerful taxonomy system, Hugo is widely used to create:
Corporate, government, nonprofit, education, news, event, and project sites Documentation sites Image portfolios Landing pages Business, professional, and personal blogs Resumes and CVs Use Hugo&amp;rsquo;s embedded web server during development to instantly see changes to content, structure, behavior, and presentation.</description></item><item><title>Features</title><link>https://gohugo.io/about/features/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gohugo.io/about/features/</guid><description>Framework Multiplatform Install Hugo&amp;rsquo;s single executable on Linux, macOS, Windows, and more. Multilingual Localize your project for each language and region, including translations, images, dates, currencies, numbers, percentages, and collation sequence. Hugo&amp;rsquo;s multilingual framework supports single-host and multihost configurations. Output formats Render each page of your site to one or more output formats, with granular control by page kind, section, and path. While HTML is the default output format, you can add JSON, RSS, CSV, and more.</description></item><item><title>Privacy</title><link>https://gohugo.io/about/privacy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gohugo.io/about/privacy/</guid><description>General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) is a regulation in EU law on data protection and privacy for all individuals within the European Union and the European Economic Area. It became enforceable on 25 May 2018.
Hugo is a static site generator. By using Hugo you are already standing on very solid ground. Static HTML files on disk are much easier to reason about compared to server and database driven websites.</description></item><item><title>Security model</title><link>https://gohugo.io/about/security/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gohugo.io/about/security/</guid><description>Runtime security Hugo produces static output, so once built, the runtime is the browser (assuming the output is HTML) and any server (API) that you integrate with.
But when developing and building your site, the runtime is the hugo executable. Securing a runtime can be a real challenge.
Hugo&amp;rsquo;s main approach is that of sandboxing and a security policy with strict defaults:
Hugo has a virtual file system and only the main project (not third-party components) is allowed to mount directories or files outside the project root.</description></item><item><title>License</title><link>https://gohugo.io/about/license/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gohugo.io/about/license/</guid><description>Apache License Version 2.0, January 2004
http://www.apache.org/licenses/
Terms and Conditions for use, reproduction, and distribution 1. Definitions “License” shall mean the terms and conditions for use, reproduction, and distribution as defined by Sections 1 through 9 of this document.
“Licensor” shall mean the copyright owner or entity authorized by the copyright owner that is granting the License.
“Legal Entity” shall mean the union of the acting entity and all other entities that control, are controlled by, or are under common control with that entity.</description></item></channel></rss>