<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Quick Reference on Hugo</title><link>https://mc.is-local.org/docs/categories/quick-reference/</link><description>Recent content in Quick Reference on Hugo</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://mc.is-local.org/docs/categories/quick-reference/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Emojis</title><link>https://mc.is-local.org/docs/quick-reference/emojis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mc.is-local.org/docs/quick-reference/emojis/</guid><description>Attribution This quick reference guide was generated using the ikatyang/emoji-cheat-sheet project which reads from the GitHub Emoji API and the Unicode Full Emoji List.
Note that GitHub custom emoji are not supported.
Usage Configure Hugo to enable emoji processing in Markdown:
hugo. yaml &amp;nbsp; toml &amp;nbsp; json &amp;nbsp; enableEmoji: true enableEmoji = true { &amp;#34;enableEmoji&amp;#34;: true } With emoji processing enabled, this Markdown:
Hello! :wave: Is rendered to:
Hello! &amp;amp;#x1f44b; And in your browser&amp;hellip; Hello!</description></item><item><title>Functions</title><link>https://mc.is-local.org/docs/quick-reference/functions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mc.is-local.org/docs/quick-reference/functions/</guid><description>cast Use these functions to cast a value from one data type to another.
cast.ToFloat (float) Converts a value to a decimal floating-point number (base 10). cast.ToInt (int) Converts a value to a decimal integer (base 10). cast.ToString (string) Converts a value to a string. collections Use these functions to work with arrays, slices, maps, and page collections.
collections.After (after) Slices an array to the items after the Nth item. collections.</description></item><item><title>Methods</title><link>https://mc.is-local.org/docs/quick-reference/methods/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mc.is-local.org/docs/quick-reference/methods/</guid><description>Duration Use these methods with time.Duration values.
Abs Returns the absolute value of the given time.Duration value. Hours Returns the time.Duration value as a floating point number of hours. Microseconds Returns the time.Duration value as an integer microsecond count. Milliseconds Returns the time.Duration value as an integer millisecond count. Minutes Returns the time.Duration value as a floating point number of minutes. Nanoseconds Returns the time.Duration value as an integer nanosecond count.</description></item><item><title>Page collections</title><link>https://mc.is-local.org/docs/quick-reference/page-collections/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mc.is-local.org/docs/quick-reference/page-collections/</guid><description>Page Use these Page methods when rendering lists on section pages, taxonomy pages, term pages, and the home page.
PAGE.Pages Returns a collection of regular pages within the current section, and section pages of immediate descendant sections. PAGE.RegularPages Returns a collection of regular pages within the current section. PAGE.RegularPagesRecursive Returns a collection of regular pages within the current section, and regular pages within all descendant sections. PAGE.Sections Returns a collection of section pages, one for each immediate descendant section of the given page.</description></item></channel></rss>