<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Contribute on Hugo</title><link>https://mc.is-local.org/docs/categories/contribute/</link><description>Recent content in Contribute on Hugo</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://mc.is-local.org/docs/categories/contribute/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Development</title><link>https://mc.is-local.org/docs/contribute/development/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mc.is-local.org/docs/contribute/development/</guid><description>Introduction You can contribute to the Hugo project by:
Answering questions on the forum Improving the documentation Monitoring the issue queue Creating or improving themes Squashing bugs Please submit documentation issues and pull requests to the documentation repository.
If you have an idea for an enhancement or new feature, create a new topic on the forum in the &amp;ldquo;Feature&amp;rdquo; category. This will help you to:
Determine if the capability already exists Measure interest Refine the concept If there is sufficient interest, create a proposal.</description></item><item><title>Documentation</title><link>https://mc.is-local.org/docs/contribute/documentation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mc.is-local.org/docs/contribute/documentation/</guid><description>Introduction We welcome corrections and improvements to the documentation. Please note that the documentation resides in its own repository, separate from the project repository.
For corrections and improvements to the current documentation, please submit issues and pull requests to the documentation repository.
For documentation related to a new feature, please include the documentation changes when you submit a pull request to the project repository.
Guidelines Markdown Please follow these guidelines:</description></item><item><title>Themes</title><link>https://mc.is-local.org/docs/contribute/themes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mc.is-local.org/docs/contribute/themes/</guid><description>Visit themes.gohugo.io to browse a collection of themes created by the Hugo community.
To submit your theme:
Read the submission guidelines Open a pull request in the themes repository Other useful theme directories:
jamstack.club jamstackthemes.dev</description></item></channel></rss>